噉。
係。
有啊！
黃定江議員，林建峯議員。
強制性公積金計劃修訂條例。
而家係首先進行二零一六年強積。
同事，誒大家好，噉啊，時間到啦。咁首先咧，就我哋係要選主席嘅。
生效日期公告，小組委員會主席嘅選舉噉，根據在於內務守則第二十二條及附錄四嘅選舉程序啦。而家係請委員提名主席一職嘅人選。
我知嘅。
啊，真。
有冇其他提名？
啊！我接受。
咁或者我應該請。
我和議啊，或者邊個和議冇所謂啊？嘅阿張麗雲議員和議。
咁誒，多謝各位。有冇需要誒選副主席？唔係啊嘛，唔係我程序係要噉樣樣。
唔係唔係，你你要上嚟主持啩？仲有冇有冇其他提有冇其他提議？就無謂調嚟調去啦。
噉我。
冇，OK。
咁誒，另外。
強積金計劃嘅。
多謝各位。噉我哋而家就進入去今日。
另外，亦都有誒強積金。
啊！一份函件，咁大家都又肯收嚟㗎啦。
嘅文件啊，大家都有喺手嚟㗎啦，噉。
嘅議程，咁首先請政府嘅官員入嚟。
誒計劃管理局嘅主管阿馮家寶女士。
法律事務部嘅報告，同埋立法會秘書處擬備嘅背景資料簡介。
或者誒趁佢哋未入嚟嗰陣時咧，我講講有關今日依個條例，咁主要咧就係。
誒生效日期嗰個背景同埋資料啦，咁財經事務及庫務局局長咧就響二零一六年十月十四號就發出咗。
誒到嚟參加呢個會議嘅有關官員，佢哋係張國財先生，佢係財經事務及副務局嘅副秘書長。
或者我首先請政府當局咧啊，就介紹一下啊，有翻有關呢份文件，咁然後咧就請啊委員咧發問。噉我首先咧就係介紹有今日。
啊！另外亦都有啊，鍾允妮女士，佢係啊局嘅助理秘書長。咁另外咧就有馬成信先生，佢係強強積金計劃管理局嘅規劃及政策總監，同埋執行董事。
但 many members don't. Many members don't want to, or they can't, and so.
管理局嘅主管姚尚敏女士。
committee being the 1st of April, 2017.
誒呢個投影片嘅介紹。啊，Darren，please，thank。
噉啊，或者首先請啊副秘書長介紹一下今日有關嘅文件，好嘛？
噉啊！亦都有政府嘅律政司高級啊，政府律師黎啟鵬先生啊，歡迎各位。
This variety of approaches across similar schemes just can't be the right approach. So that's that was the basis upon which this project started. That we needed some consistency in that approach to deal with this choice complexity issue.
Each scheme has to have rules about what happens in that case when members don't do it. At the moment, this isn't regulated at all. So this has been left to individual providers to make up their own rules. In essence, we're not the only place in the world that does this, but that's the background as to how that happened. As a consequence, as you can see from this slide.
一個法例咧就係關於誒強積金嘅預設投資策略嘅。咁其實呢個法例咧就喺上一屆立法會係今年嘅五月份咧已經係通過咗嘅。咁而今次我哋講咧就係話佢幾時實施嘅。咁呢個係一個關於實施日期嘅一個附屬法例。咁誒，因為我都知識咧就誒呢個委員會入邊咧係有一啲。
新嘅立法會委員咁所誒立法會議員噉，所以咧，我哋都準備咗一個即係投影片咧，就係詳細解釋翻呢一個誒法例。雖然佢已經通過咗呢個法例，關於二設投資策略嘅一啲誒誒安排嘅。噉我而家先請咧，就係強積金管理局嘅馬誠信先生為我哋做一個。
Thank you, Chairman. Let me take members briefly through a little bit of the background as to how how we get to this point. As Mr. Chung has said, the legislation has already been discussed, but I'll take you through some of the background as to how we get here. The starting premise is that within MPF, members do have choices about how they can invest their benefits.
different scheme to come up with different answers. So some used mixed asset funds which might have a higher risk exposure. Some use conservative funds. Some use a range of things. In a couple of cases, they just spread the benefits across all the funds in the scheme. Now, no matter what view one takes about what's the right approach, the fact that there
There's been a long developmental process in this, including a public consultation back in two thousand and fourteen, through to introduction of the legislation by the end of fifteen. And as Mr. Chong said, the passage of the bill as recently as May, the proposed implementation date, which is the objective for this.
所以，what the legislation does, it requires every trustee to do the same thing. Basically, as I said, to date they do different things. So the objective of this is just to get them to do the same thing. So there are some provisions in the amendment ordinance which require the trustees to provide the standardised thing, and importantly, the standardised.
Approach has a fee control, and the name we provide for this because it applies to those who don't make the decision themselves is the default investment strategy. So it's a strategy that applies to the contributions from those who don't give instructions. So this has an impact. It's true on the accounts of many scheme members.
This slide.
reducing.
In this strategy, will be invested in a diversified manner.
exposure to higher risk assets as a member gets older.
The mechanism we do that is a little bit complicated, but in essence, the way we've done it is to.
as subject to how they integrate with the system at the moment. But the simplest case is new members from 1st April.
as little change as possible. So we need two new constituent funds. As members may know, a MPF scheme has got a number of investment options.
Anywhere from five to 20, on a typical scheme, and these are core constituent funds. So we need true constituent funds to achieve the de-risking and strategy I just mentioned.
Setting up a new account. If they don't give instructions, then obviously as a default, the investments will go into the DIS. That's the whole premise of of the new law. So that's that's relatively simple. There are some transitional provisions.
In the system, so this focuses on going forward. To take the second point there, for new members coming in, the the impact of this starting on the 1st of April is that from a new member coming in on that day.
unless they give instructions or until they give instructions, then their contributions will go into the default investment strategy. A large part of the law and more of the technical part of the development, which took a long time to work through with the industry, and we discussed that some length with members through the bills committee process, was
seek to give you an idea of how this affects different types of members. On the whole, for most members who've already given instructions in relation to their accounts, this has no impact on them whatsoever, and that is the vast majority of members, the vast majority of accounts, and the vast majority of money.
about what happens to current accounts. The new world is always easy in these types of movements. It's the transitional provisions which do have some complexity. So the the legislation does provide some transitional provisions about how this affects existing scheme members. Obviously, as I said, this only affects those existing scheme.
Members who've not given instructions for any of the benefits in their account, and for those types of accounts, there's a process by which they'll be moved into the default investment strategy over time. And I'll speak a little bit more about that process in a minute. As I said, for the most members who've given their instructions, the actual commencement on the first the eight.
April would not affect them, but of course they have the option to choose to invest in the default investment strategy from that date. So they can give new instructions at any point in time from that date to invest their existing or future benefits in this new default investment strategy. So it has slightly different impacts on different members.
If you go to have a standardised approach, well, what how what is the standardised investment approach? So a lot of the legislative provisions go to how this actually is invest, and that is set out in some detail. And there are a couple of principles there. Firstly, that we're going to achieve the most diversification benefits that we can. So the benefits.
And importantly, because we need to deal with, in an average sense, how we best protect members, the real risk and long-term investment is what happens right at the end. And the analysis we did showed that this is where members can really get hurt if things go bad right at the end. So the propose the the law provides for.
在establishing and promoting and distributing the scheme, custodians.
Provide good value to members, and it's the combination of those two proposals that achieve that.
In contrast, when you get to the end of the working life and to pass the retirement age, as or claim age as it's called.
是invested in riskier assets，that is that means equities and shares， and forty percent invested in lower assets， lower risk assets。
From age 64 and 65 onwards, the member will be 100% invested in the lower risk fund, the age 65 plus fund. So that's the mechanism we've used and is set out in the law to achieve that de-risking.
Specifically, sets out a mechanism for uplifting the costs and fees at the lower level, so that all of that is captured holistically in that 0.75% of net asset value each year. This is actually a daily cap set out in the law, but on an annual basis, this works out at 0.75%.
所以我們需要一個流程，為移動人從那個年齡50到那個年齡65，和那係一些技術性嘅設計嘅部分。所以我們有呢啲步驟，理論上，點樣將人從一個移動到另一個？我們嘅方法係逐步將錢從核心積蓄基金移出。
The investment approach is we've taken the risk off the table by that stage. So there's a constituent fund called the Age 65 Plus Fund, which is only 20% equity. So that's much lower risk, and that's the fund that money will stay on from age 65, or technically actually age 64 in the way it works in the law.
The way it works is that up until age 50, a member's contributions to the DIS will be invested wholly in this constituent fund called the Core Accumulation Fund, and the pink bit there represents the risky assets in that in that particular constituent fund. So 60% of that fund
And put it into the age 65 fund. So between age 50 and 64, people will have some money in both of those funds. But each year, the trustee, the member doesn't have to do anything. The trustee will automatically move some of the money out of the higher risk fund and put more in the lower risk fund. So at the end of that glide path, as we call it.
The other important element, as members know, is that the default investment strategy comes with with fee and expense controls. This was an important part of dealing with members' concerns about the cost of their interaction with NPS providers. The fee control in the law, as a starting point, is 0.75 of the fund value each year.
所以， implement time frame for this.
There are a couple of exceptions to that, and we discussed some of these at length in Bills Committee previously.
This fund, and if they don't want to make any choice, well, that's exactly what this is designed for. They'll end up in the default investment strategy.
And this looks a little bit to the transition. So how do we deal with this complex issue of those current accounts where there are no instructions?
那 Transitional requirement about these are accounts that have got no instructions and are wholly invested in the current default.
on the assumption that this commences in April 2017, the law sets out a transitional period as to how this works. Within that six months.
基金，我們不希望他們被 denied the benefit of the promise contained in the guarantee，所以 trustee has to do some work to work out whether the member would be better off。
把所有錢放到核心積蓄基金，someone between 50到65，They invest it in accordance with the allocations I mentioned in one of the previous slides. So the trustee will do all that for the member. The member doesn't have to do anything. This is about relieving the burden from the member of having to work through that.
Yeah， and this covers all of the payments for the services of the providers indicated on the right. So trustees, administrators do all the all the administration work. Obviously, there's also investment managers who do a totally different function. The investment work also falls within that. The work that the sponsors and promoters do.
On the whole, and the same types of funds that are charged to lower level funds are included in the rather complex calculation. We provided guidelines as to how to apportion these across the CF level and underlying fund level, because we don't want people just be able to hide this at underlying funds. So the law.
The other cap within the law is an expense control beyond fees, which are sort of a profit item or an item to cover the cost of providing the services from certain parties that are indicated on the previous slide. There are expenses, so there are things that come out of funds which are actual acquittals on.
basis of a cost incurred, so these these are incurred by the fund and include things like auditor's fee and lots of miscellaneous things, printing expenses, bank charges, government fees, and these are defined in the law. So these are subject to a different cap, which is also
which is an annual cap of can't exceed more than 20 points, so 0.2% of the net asset value of the fund. So in combination, these are considered as important constraints on the way that fees and expenses will affect the returns of members in the default investment strategy. Considered important if we're designing defaults that they have to be able to.
In terms of how that works for members, so at the end of the day, there's this new thing—the default investment strategy for people who don't make choices. But the law also requires that the default investment strategy itself is a choice, so people can choose that. So this becomes a new choice option for people as well, for those who want to make choices.
And they can decide, for instance, to consciously choose to invest 100% in the devolved investment strategy, or they still preserve all their other rights to choose other constituent funds. So they can choose above or below the line if they want to put part of the money in a variety of funds. They can do so, including.
The two new funds, the two constituent funds I mentioned, that are part of the default investment strategy. So members will be able to allocate their investment choice across the range of constituent funds, including those two new ones. So that's in effect a new range of choice available for members beyond the ability just to invest everything in.
The affected accounts will get a notice from the trustees. It's the trustee's job to identify these accounts and to send out a notice to all of these accounts within that first six months. The member then has 42 days, and what the notice says is that unless I hear from you in the next 42 days, this account will be invested in the defaul
investment strategy going forward. So that's what the notice says. So the member has that 42 days to get back to the trustee and say, no, I want to do something else. Up to this point, they've done nothing, but this is a fresh opportunity for them to make a decision. They could make that decision any time from today. In essence, they can give instructions to the trustee and fall outside that provision. But this is
that this is coming.
particular phases.
The next phase will be a larger scale campaign once.
commencing the legislation on the 1st of April 2017.
可以apply for trustee failure to comply with the obligations.
There's provisions for auditors and service providers to report any non-compliance to the authority.
和，the authority can actually request auditors' investigation and report in relation to any concerns that we might have.
provision and regulation, if there is any failure to comply, so our existing powers are extended to the DIS as well as some new provisions.
So in terms of the process of this committee, the commencement notice was tabled on the 19th of October, with a target of introducing the.
that it'll have an impact on them, and to encourage them to check with the trustees, because that's where they have to go to check with the trustees that their address is up to date, for instance, so that they will get the important communication which will come very shortly.
and importantly, reminding people for those who will be affected, you will get this transitional notice sometime in the next six months, and reminding them of how important that is to them and the action required of members both in advance of that and after they receive that notice.
for those who've not by the time the notices are sent out made any choice, they get the notice and they've got forty two days to get back to the trustee. If they do not get back, then the obligation on the trustee is within the next fourteen days to invest that account in accordance with the default investment strategy. So for someone under fifty, that means they.
That will not apply to members who are over sixty on commencement date, so on the one st of April. And the reason for that being, there seemed little point in changing their asset allocation when they're so close to being able to withdraw the benefits from the system. The second category who will get the notice, but there's a special rule about those who are currently invested in guarantee.
whether the guarantee has value, and if the guarantee has value, the member stays in the guarantee fund. And the actual requirements on the trustee are set out in the law, so they're set out. In terms of regulation and supervision, of course, the bill also sets out provisions about extending the NPFA's powers in relation to super.
The law also sets out the consequences if there's failure to comply with any of these obligations, and there's lots of obligations in there on trustees. The consequences being the possibilities of revocation as an approved trustee, in the most serious cases, suspension or termination of scheme administration, and also a range of financial penalties that.
Of course, since the passage of the bill, the authority and the industry has been actively involved in trying to educate members and make them more aware of this thing that is coming because it's a big change. Up to this point, the authority has been engaged in one particular campaign. We split this into three.
The first part being a from June to November, sort of a preparatory campaign to get people interested enough to perhaps go and check what their current status is, so they're not surprised about what may happen next year in relation to their account. So we've engaged in advertisements in newspapers and websites to remind members.
There there is a clear commencement date and that is passed. Then we will start a campaign in a little more detail about the features of the DIS to let people know what's coming and to remind them that they will be getting important notices. And importantly, they will get something in all likelihood before the end of the year because the
啊，陸議員。
陸仲雄議員。
議員，我們有。
That they should check that they are aware of their accounts and the contact details are up to date.
and this continues the theme of emphasising for those industry scheme casual employees.
There have been specific activities around certain types of accounts, casual employees, under the industry schemes.
睇下委員有啲咩問題咧，就一係有啲官員喺度咧，即係大家都可以問一問啊。咁首先係。
誒多謝主席。噉我或者我讀一讀啦。阿陳建波跟住係陳建波議員、張超雄議員、潘兆平議員同埋周鴻鼎議員。
啊，係已經討論咗通過咗，咁但係基於我哋今屆咧係有一啲新委員嘅，咁所以咧我都啊。
誒都係主席，噉我哋工聯會一直都好關注即係強積金嘅回報啊，各方面嘅嘢，同埋收費問題。噉啊就住咧誒呢個。
D.I.S. issues as they develop. The focus at the moment is, as I said, encouraging members to be involved enough to perhaps check their account status and make sure that the trustee has their contact details so they can receive the important communication to come.
Some of the publicity material here, if members are interested, I won't take members through them individually, but of course we will have a range of newspaper, online and search engine based advertisements. We have a dedicated webpage on our website dealing specifically with.
amendments to all the documentation will be sent to members along with a detailed notice about the impact on their account. And the third phase, of course, will be after this commences. The authority, with the support of the industry, will commence a large-scale publicity campaign, again emphasising the details of the DIs implementation.
Have a different set of issues. Many of those accounts didn't have as much contact information as master trust accounts, so we had specific campaigns related to that, and then been some specific activities around high publicity events such as horse racing opportunities to remind those people.
and assisting them to make sure that they have they are within contact of their trustee and they're interested in what's happening to their account, including a mobile text message to all employees in the construction industry. So there's a variety of strategies adopted to make sure people know what's happening and what's coming in that respect. Chairman, that brings us.
up to date with preparation to date， we're happy， of course， to take members' question。啊，thank you，Darren。啊，我都想啊，首先同委員講講咧，有關文件嘅內容咧，其實係響上一屆六月嗰陣時咧已經係通過咗㗎啦。咁今個呢個委員會要處理嘅咧就係。
啊！依個立法程序嘅時間表，咁咧主要係有三個日期嘅，就係審議期屆滿嘅日期，同埋向內會啊內務委員會報告嘅日期，啊，同埋就動議修訂附屬法例作出預告嘅限期。咁雖然，
啊，邊位回應啊？
即係或者我冇落嗰個投資指示咧，先至會跌落去嘅啫。呢度可能呢會有啲公眾嘅誤解，所以亦都要加強嗰個宣傳教育咯。嚇，唔該主席。
咧，我覺得呢個誒新嘅即係條例實施咗之後咧，都成個強積金嘅市場咧轉變都係相當之大嘅。
誒嘅條例咧，其實我哋喺上一屆咧都提出過一啲嘅修訂，噉就遺憾咧未能夠通過嘅。但係都希望咧喺新一屆咧，我哋繼續咧係關注嗰個。
特別係除咗一啲咧，即係冇指示嘅自動撥咗落呢個啊預設基金嗰度咧嚇，其實咧如果你話誒，佢中間嗰個叫做係。
譬如嗰個國家嘅受託人嘅基金嘅回報嘅排名啦，嚇有係嘅情況係點樣咧？仲有咧，都想問一問一個好具體嘅問題。
咁對於可能係嗯即係投資者嚟講咧係有利嘅，咁呢方面咧其實都係值得去宣傳推廣，因為如果咪有啲人咧就係以為我冇選擇咧。
如果係因為一啲未知數咧，而去作出一啲罰則咧，我哋覺得係並不適合嘅。即係我哋嗰陣時做一個比喻就係，我哋冇可能話要即係個天文台好準確，真係預測天氣嘅，即係一定係有啲落差嘅。咁但係當然我哋係明白咧，回報咧係誒一啲誒計劃成員咧。
誒回報嘅管制啦，係咪會有啲機制？即係如果嗰個回報係低於某個水平，誒，譬如可能係用一個通脹做指標，咁應該有啲懲罰嚇。可能係扣減嗰個誒管理費啊，甚至乎係咪要研究佢嗰個誒受託人嘅資格咧？咁同埋嗰個收費咧，七。
七點五個percent加兩個percent咧，好多市民都覺得係仍然未夠低嘅。咁是否咧會定一個即係檢討嘅機制咧？啊，最好嘅一年一檢啦，係咪？咁同埋透明度方面咧，我覺得而家積金局咧喺嗰個投資回報嗰方面咧，畀公眾嘅信息咧係唔夠嘅。
就係誒積金局有冇估計咧？誒而家即係用而家嘅情況，係冇做投資誒指示嘅比例有幾多？咁如果實施咗呢條新例之後咧，自動撥入呢個預設基金嘅又有幾多？咁最後一個咧就係嗰個宣傳教育嗰方面。
核心累積基金，核心累積基金，其實佢嗰個誒投資組合咧都幾似以往一啲基金裏邊嘅誒中度風險嘅投資組合嘅嘅嘢嚟嘅。咁但係以前咧可能一點五個percent啊，或者更高嘅管理費，咁呢個相對平嘅。
啊，或者我我簡單回應咧，如果有需要，我可以誒請阿阿馬成信先生咧去補充嘅。啊，主席，噉係誒，的確嘅，喺誒上誒討論呢個條例嗰個泛委員會嗰陣時咧，即係工聯會都提出好多嘅意見。咁不過必須強調咧，就係誒回報咧，的確係一啲未知數嚟嘅。咁
係好誒希望知道嘅嘢，咁其實咧積金局咧係有個平台，佢係將每一個誒強積金嗰個基金咧嗰個回報咧係一年啊、三年啊、五年啊、十年啊嗰個年化率嗰個回報咧，其實係有喺度嘅。咁誒啲誒委員咧誒啲成員咧係可以好容易咧去上呢個網上嘅平台咧作出個比。
跟住落嚟係請張超雄議員。
O.K.唔該，Eddie。啊，跟住係請陳建波議員。
嗰個溝通啊，佢哋嘅電腦又做成點啊，佢哋嗰啲人手又做成點？我想你講一講呢樣嘢。
啊，Eddie，係誒主席誒，多謝誒陳議員嘅提問。噉我哋係同誒業界係有個商討，噉係誒業界係誒誒有信心咧，係喺四月一號咧係準備走水嘅。
哦，咁所以我咪自己可以作出一個誒決定，去揀呢一個有收費管制嘅累積經紀費係完全可以做。噉我哋係完全同意啊，陸議員嘅説法，我哋應該係會做多啲宣傳嘅。
啲條例出嚟咧，好多人都有好多問題，就係響嗰個條例生效之後嘅。咁如果係由而家去到四月一號咧，係做多依一方面嘅工作咧，我諗對各方面都係係有好處嘅嚇。
教嘅噉我哋都好樂意咧，係再做多啲宣傳咧，係等誒啲成員咧係可以知道點樣用呢個平台去比較一啲回報嘅。噉啊，我哋亦都係承諾咗咧，係三年實行咗呢一個預設投資策略之後嘅三年咧，就會嚟立法會即係會彙報一下啦，即係我哋嗰個檢討嘅。咁點解三年咧？就因為我哋。
講緊咧一啲比較長線嘅投資嘅，咁誒，我哋就唔想即係只係依賴譬如一年嘅一個數據咧，就作出一個即係誒武斷嘅一個誒誒結論。咁所以我哋覺得即係三年之後咧，先做一個檢討咧，佢會比較適合。咁當然啦，我哋可以不斷即係同誒立法會嘅議員咧，係即係定期咧。
我哋去即係彙報一下嗰個成效啊，各樣嘢嘅執行嗰個成效噉。咁誒誒，我好贊成啊！頭先陸議員提嗰度嘅，因為我哋有呢個收費管制咧，其實我哋第一次。噉我哋亦都頭先啊馬誠信先生嗰個介紹咧，就睇到咧一個誒計劃成員咧，佢係唔需要誒揀呢個誒住。
設投資計劃嘅，佢仲有一個選擇咧，係可以直接咧係揀呢個有收費管制嘅累積基金或者個六税税後嘅基金嘅。咁所以咧，如果一個成員佢覺得就係話我自己都識做呢啲噉嘅風險調整啊，但係我又想咧係誒受惠於呢一個噉嘅收費管制喎。
主席，誒保險界咧都係做呢個強積金嘅機構，都喺呢個法案委員會都講咗好多啦。主要就係話嗰個擔心咧係，如果市民唔瞭解呢個對佢哋影響咧，就冇選擇呢個退出嘅話咧，結果就會有後果，又話將來好多年後會翻嚟。
點解將海錢搬曬去一啲誒？由以前可能佢係好低風險嘅，轉去高風險嘅。噉我哋當然係建議選擇加入嘅啊。即係如果佢係覺得佢需要轉去呢個要呢個預設投資策略咧，佢就選擇加入。咁但係當然我哋要誒個結果就大家投票都覺得話係可以容許係呢個選擇退出。
啦，噉我哋覺得呢個唔理想嘅，咁大家都冇辦法啦，因為而家大個決定都咁做啦，咁所以就好依賴嗰個宣傳教育工作啦。噉我而家睇到你呢度亦都有即係相當誒多嘅資源或者個計劃咧，係做呢個宣傳教育工作啦。不過我希望你嗰個宣傳嘅重點咧都要講咧，就係話如果嗰個誒基金。
或者搶搶誒搶資金嘅成員咧，如果佢喺收到個通知四十日四廿二日之內係一定要回覆嘅，即係希望你個宣傳個重點一個最重要就係話畀佢一定回覆，你唔回覆咧嗰啲錢咧就會去咗呢個核心基金啦。即係我諗佢要呢個重點一定要出到啦，就唔好出咗其他啲話咩重唔重要或者其他嘢。
Darren.
Thank you, Chairman. Let me.
零點二percent咧，相對於現有。
Let me emphasise that, so we manage the expectations going forward. But it should approximate it. So, on the whole, that's broadly in the park. So
Your observation is correct. The the tracker fund's management expense ratio, which is calculated quite differently to our fund expense ratio.
Strategy's who are interested in working with our trustees, so we're excited about the possibility of getting those costs down quite dramatically as part of this implementation.
基金咧，其實佢嗰個費用咧，就仍然遠遠低過呢一個即係誒收費嘅或者開支嘅上限嘅。
喺市場上邊嘅貨品嚟講咧，即係究竟係誒已經係屬於低到幾多咧？係咪誒最低咧？即係個percentage啦，即係我唔知中文係叫咩，屬於係係幾多咧？噉樣可唔可以都同我哋講講呢啲？
最緊要都係要講畀佢聽咧。如果佢喺嗰四日天，四啊二天之外唔唔回覆咧，誒嗰個機構咧，佢結果就會將啲錢自動轉去呢一啲核心基金啦。噉就當然跟佢嘅歲數就嗰個風險會會啊，當然係不斷咁減少啦嚇。咁但係都始終係有一個係一個比較即係進取啲。
嘅投資策略噉，所以希望咧就係誒第一，政府即係或者係強積金局咧喺呢個宣傳嘅內容嗰度咧，一定要有呢個重點出到嚟先得嚇。呢個第一啦，第二咧都想問一問，究竟業界準備好未咧？因為你而家話係四月一號開始啊，噉我想問一問政府咧同誒呢個強積金嗰啲誒服務提供者。
咁頭先嗰個宣傳策略嗰啲，哦係誒誒，主席誒，多謝陳議員嘅意見，我哋會即係誒誒誒參考你個意見，我哋會即係個重點都係各方面咧。誒呢個一個好好嘅意見，我哋一定會接受啊。我諗陳議員提出嗰點喺宣傳嗰方面，或者甚至都教育嗰方面咧，應該要做多啲唔多嘅過去有一。
誒主席誒，當然即係呢個漁池投資策略，我哋係歡迎嘅。誒，雖然佢未盡完善，包括咗即係所收嘅一啲費用或者開支咧，其實都有空間去繼續下降。如果我哋淨係睇盈富。
咁但係即係點都好啦，我都想理解一下誒，就住呢一個機制咧，其實我唔知道當局有冇做過啲模擬嘅誒預測，即係話誒用翻呢一個投資策略咧，係或者有高中低嘅一啲嘅唔同嘅情況底下。
大概每年即係以過去嗰一段時間，可能過去嗰五年、十年，誒呢個收費同埋嗰個誒開支，即係嗰個誒return嗰個叫回報啊，大概係幾多啦？同埋而家嗰個管理費用零點七五percent咧，同埋個開支。
Try to answer those questions. We agree, there's room for lowering fees. These need to be established, and as Mr. Chung has said, that needs to be reviewed going forward. In terms of your question of the fees and the FER, yes, FER has come down. Two thousand and seven, when these figures were first available, the average expense ratio figure was two. one
Risking that we do 15 years from the end is designed to deal with that and protect members from those bad outcomes.
問題，咁大家都關心嘅，不不論你係勞資或者係管理。
The scenario analysis, I give you a very long answer on this, but I'll try to be brief. We did a lot of work, and we had retained a consultant from the OECD to work with us on doing scenario analysis of different investment strategies.
誒有關基金嘅公司咧，嚇喺呢一方面都希望政府可以做多一啲宣傳。噉係咪可以除咗一啲傳統嘅誒宣傳方法，啊有一啲正話你話講話報紙？
可以用一個最簡單嘅方式去誒表示佢將願意將佢自己嗰個投資咧轉為呢個新嘅誒漁漬投資策略，噉就會最方便啦。咁呢呢樣嘢咧就可以。
知嘅，我就想問政府當局會唔會都要求而家嗰啲誒積金強積金嗰啲嘅誒嘅管理公司咧，都畀一個通知畀所有嘅誒有強積金户口嘅誒成員，讓佢哋。
That's now one fifty six. So that figure has dropped about a quarter in that period. But yes, that figure is still well above the figure one gets to if you extrapolate from the two caps here. I should say those. If you add up the zero seventy five and zero two, that does not necessarily exactly equal an FERF.
Yes, these funds will be significantly lower than the average. They're also lower than the vast majority of funds. We do have some low fee funds at the moment, but these new funds will all be well below the benchmark for getting onto that list. So, so that is important. In terms of the tracker.
是 very low, perhaps twenty basis points or lower, but that only represents the investment management component. It's to be remembered that the largest part of that seventy five doesn't relate to investment management. It relates to the administration of, of the M P F scheme, which is quite different to administering just an exchange traded fund.
你 may remember we used a consultant to do some work on estimating the cost of administration a few years ago. Ernst and Young's report calculated that the cost of administration, ignoring that investment part, was seventy five points, which suggests that the seventy five is quite an aggressive because it does include the investment costs.
Of things like tracker, we're still looking at the applications coming in, but many of them are adopting a passive index-based approach. So, as far as the investment part goes, yes, we'd be expecting some of the investment costs to be getting down towards those sorts of ranges. And there are some larger providers of index-type.
to cut a long story short, yes, you get a huge dispersion of returns depending on your strategy. To take the tracker fund, of course, the average would have been higher. But Hong Kong equities, we would have left a lot of people with very bad outcomes at the end because of the volatility. And we also modelled pure cash and everything in between. The approach we got to at the end through his work.
And working with the industry and our observations about how others are doing this around the world is the strategy we have. Overall equity exposure in the low 50s between those two funds, so about 53%. But importantly, to remove that tailed risk of things going really wrong at the end is the scenario that that he worked on, and so the.
好誒，我仲有一個跟進問題咧，就係關於誒而家我哋會通通知啦，同埋有個誒公告日期之後咧。誒，我留意到有好多即係有強積金嘅打工仔女咧，其實佢唔係好知自己而家個投資策略係點，究竟佢係。
係咪已經擺咗喺預設投資策略啊？定係話擺咗喺啲咩基金咧？佢唔清楚。咁當然啦，如果你話新入嘅或者已經擺咗誒預設投資策略嘅，就自動轉帳落到呢個核心基金，咁呢個冇問題啊。但係嗰啲唔係嘅，佢可能。
即係我哋而家明知呢一個嘅誒收費會比較係合理啦，同埋即係如果根據頭先所講嗰個誒做咗唔同嘅投資分析，亦都會覺得而家呢個分析咧，根據嗰個年齡噉樣分佈咧，係可能係一個最好嘅風險管理。噉係咪？
即係應該更加讓所有嘅強積金嘅打工仔女容易啲進入呢一個噉樣嘅新嘅安排咧。好，阿Eddy主席，誒多謝阿張議員嘅誒意見啊。噉係我哋係會做嘅，因為點解咧？而家我哋講緊咧就係話，每一個受託人都要喺每一個強積金。
對。
誒嘅安排咧，唔該。
Darren。
費嗰度咧，我哋都明白到咧，就係。
哦，Eddy，哦，Darren。
跟住係請周浩鼎議員。
啊，基金嘅大小啊，參加嘅人數咧係會影響到個收費嘅，但係。
參加者最重要嘅咧就係你收費低迴報高嚇，咁依個咧即係我都希望你哋一路落去咧都關注依一點。
嘅計劃咧係加兩個基金，因為呢個預算投資上有兩個基金，咁所以咧佢係必須咧係要發信畀所有嘅強積金成員咧係通知佢將會有呢兩個新嘅基金。咁而當我哋實施嗰陣時咧，就再會做一次咧，就係話畀一啲係將誒從來冇做過投資決定。
嘅一啲成員就係話，希望你喺四十誒二日之內咧作出一個決定。噉，如果你冇決定咧，我哋先會轉嘅。咁亦都咧，我哋其實而家咧，強積金管理局咧已經係做咗好多宣傳。誒，你哋可能都會喺報章留意到，就係你有冇收到強積金呢封信啦。咁呢一啲宣傳嘅咁呢個宣傳咧，我。
我完全同意，議員咧係我哋個重中之重，係一個非常之誒誒誒重要嘅一個重點工作嚟嘅嚇。多謝議員。我想澄清，即係話咧，呢啲嘅受託人咧將會有一個信息畀所有嘅户口持有人，然後佢哋只係要簡單顯示話佢願意將現有嘅。
佢嘅户口嘅資金轉移到呢兩個核心基金，或者跟呢個預設投資策略嘅話咧，噉就可以完成呢個工作㗎啦。係，但係就要四月一號先可以做呢個動作。係啦，多謝主席。其實張亞陳建波陳建波議員咧都提出過一個宣傳教育過問。
啊，我覺得喺報章上邊誒個宣傳咧，係咪真係咁大效力咧？因為而家好多人真係唔係睇報紙嘅嚇。咁依個或者你去考慮一下。最重要嘅咧就大家都知道，啊有一個新制度喺度嚇，大家點樣可以去處理？咁至於嗰個管理。
跟住落嚟係請潘兆平議員。誒，多謝主席。啊，呢條條例咧就響五月即係通過啦，噉我都支持。噉啊，當然咧而家個實施日期響出年四月咧。咁其實我我我都同意，即係要加強嗰個宣傳，呢個係必要。咁其實我主要想問一個好簡單問題，因為由呢條條例。
到而家已經半年啦。咁理論上咧就誒，以往冇去選擇投資嗰啲顧員，其實佢都而家可以選擇翻自己應該要選擇。我想知道啊，有冇咩變動響？即係我掌握到而家嗰個狀況之下，即係以前冇選擇嘅顧員啊，佢哋有冇變動？佢自己主動去選擇咗一啲。
We have been working with trustees to get a better feel for how many accounts are affected by the transitional provisions. Those numbers do seem to have come down since we first asked this question during the Bills Committee last year. Whether that's because the data is better and the trustees are looking at it closer, or because people are actually making choices, we can't disaggregate. To be perfectly honest.
啊，Eddy。
有其他畀佢更加降低咧，降低嘅風險咧噉。第二咧就係誒，我留意到咧。
有共識，但係業界、學術界，和有 regard to 什麼 done 其他地方，我們認為這是最好的方法，雖然
What I was referring to is the transitional process. So, for current accounts, whilst most for those affected accounts for people who haven't given instructions at the moment.
你哋本身已經係根據翻間銀本身嗰間銀行，可能提供咗畀佢，就知道誒，我哋已經答應咗畀咁多個回報你，所以我哋就唔會畀你轉過去嗰度啦。噉係咪個銀行去決定嘅咧？咁主要係呢幾個問題啫。唔該。
Although anecdotally, on the basis of the discussion with the trustees, we don't see that there have been a lot of people who are rushing in to make new choices. So I'd have to say there's not been a surge of people moving out of defaults into something else at this stage. There are two two sides of this coin though, of course, and the one.
sense， yes， it reduces an administrative issue. The more people make choices， but the more people make choices， the fewer will end up in the DIs. So we need to be cautious about this. And we've sent out guidelines or circular letters to the sales forces to tell them to be very careful. Be careful what you're telling people here， because if you go in， it gives
them advice about individual fund choices they should be making. You've got to do suitability assessments. You can't just say don't invest in the DIS or do invest in the DIS. They have to actually have a basis for making that having regard to individual circumstances. So we're asking the industry to be very cautious and careful in relation to what they say about that.
誒唔該，主席啊，其實都有好幾個問題想請教嘅。咁誒，如果我有重複咗，因為頭先行行咗出去，咁大家再誒冇介意咁誒。第一個問題咧，我就留意到咧，嗯，今次呢個核心基金佢嗰個做咧，佢有六十個percent係會放喺一啲。
誒所謂風險較高嘅投資嗰度嘅咁誒，我想問下，因為原先我驚我有誤會，我早期聽到咧做嗰個核心基金嘅時候咧，都係因為諗住即係可能畀一啲冇冇自己冇選擇嘅噉就擺落去啦。咁咁呢個核心基金嚟講咧，誒會唔會個？
想睇下佢究竟同一啲而家現行做緊一啲低風險嗰啲基金係點比較咧？即係睇嚟，因為呢個核心基金都擺到成六十percent係風險比較高嘅。咁其實誒，我想了解下佢而家同一啲現行緊嘅低風險嘅基金究竟點比較咧？係咪佢已經係最低啊？還是即係當然仲有？
誒，你哋都話咧，而家咧係可以誒自己去選擇，即係嗰個人如果揀咧，佢可以自行選擇翻核心累積基金或者六十五歲後基金，佢可以自己選擇嘅。我想問喺呢個過程喺呢個情況嚟講咧，嗰個收費係咪都係bound to low咧？定零點七五percent嘅，即係我想肯定下呢樣嘢啫嚇。咁仲有一個。
個問題咧，我就睇到咧，就文件裏面講咧，誒，因為喺一七年嘅四月一號之前咧，如果係年滿咗六十歲而又冇作投資選擇嘅成員咧，就誒唔可以轉過嚟今次預設基金嘅。我主要想了解下嗰個理由啊，咁即係我想我想了解下咁啫。咁同埋。
埋咧就因為另外一個條件咧，就係話誒誒，如果係本身嗰個成員咧，佢係有一啲誒做咗一啲保證基金嗰啲承諾回報。如果佢當然即係參加咗呢個D.I.S.之後咧，嗰個回報會低於佢嗰個承諾回報咧，就唔會鼓勵，即係唔會畀佢轉翻嚟。咁呢個我完全明白嘅。不過我想問係點樣judge嘅？係咪？
Chair, let me try to answer those sequentially. The core accumulation fund, yes, is generally riskier than most current defaults. If you look at the current range of defaults, some schemes use the conservative fund, which is much lower risk. That's almost no risk. Some use guarantee, but some also use target date fund, so they've got some equity content. Exactly in the same way as we.
Under this proposal, some use mixed asset funds. So, but I would concede that on the average, this solution, the core accumulation fund does take on more risk. But it does so deliberately because part of the consequence of leaving this to trustees' discretion or providers' discretion in the past is they take the they have ten.
to take the approach not just here in Hong Kong but elsewhere in the world that is the least trouble to them so that they will face less issues but that's not necessarily the best result for members the sort of scenario analysis we did I referred to in the previous answer was very much looking at this issue so what's the consequence at the end of the day after 40 years saving of taking these different approaches and as a matter
第。
我在呢個。
誒個slide度。
O.K.唔該，咁跟住係請中國軍議員。
一發嗰個誒個個準則情況係點嘅？
At any time after 1st of April, they can go into the defaults.
預設投資策略裏邊咧，第四啊，第四版。
呢個第一個問題，第二個問題咧就係嗰個時間表。個時間表就係話四月一號之後咧。
唔該，主席，有幾個問題想少澄清嘅啫。第一個問題咧，就係喺嗰個。
就算佢哋係四月一號之前冇轉嘅咧，四月一號之後只要佢要求，都係可以轉嘅。
佢呢度講講嘅咧，就係話修訂條例要求每名受託人需在每個強積金計劃下提供一套高度劃一。
誒，即係第十六版，即係四月一號之後咧，就有六十天嘅條例實施起計嘅六個月時間，就通知所有嘅誒。
We take them out of this 60% equity fund from age 50, so that we reduce the prospect of things going very bad towards the end. But yes, this is higher risk than many of the current default approaches. I'd agree with that. In terms of choice, if people choose these two constituent funds, yes, they get the benefit of the fee caps, even if they're not doing it through.
DIS， if they choose the core accumulation fund or the age sixty five plus fund, yes, they get the benefit of the zero seven five management fee cap. Okay. Okay. In terms of the switching, perhaps I didn't describe that very well. Nothing prevents anyone over sixty five or anyone in a guarantee fund from switching to the default investment strategy.
They will get the letter. If they don't respond, then they'll automatically be moved. That doesn't apply in those two particular cases. So it's only for those transitional accounts. So and the reason we didn't do it for the over six those over sixty is we thought it probably not best to move them automatically without they necessarily doing any.
因為他們所以接近退休，那的投資策略，我們採 adopted，just won't have time to have impact。所以，我們把他們拉出來，但他們可以，而且他們會被告訴，通過我們的通知，我們會給每個人都知道，他們可以做選擇來投資這些。所以，只要他們提供給你同意，它就可以轉移。像其他人一樣。
The same with the guarantee fund. The concept with the guarantee fund is they're a bit different. We have problems like with these. Well, what's going to happen in the future is one thing, but we we've taken the brave decision that we have a default approach for going forward. So, yeah, there'll be winners and losers in that, but we've made that decision. For guarantees, it's a bit.
different because you've got accrued benefits, you've got accrued rights, and we didn't want to take people out of a guarantee fund where the value of what they've already accrued would be lost. So there's some calculations which are a little complex for the trustees to do in that case, but that's a special case. Again, though, if the member wants to.
設收費管制嘅預設投資策略呢個高度劃一嘅準則係誒呢班誒trust trustee佢哋自己坐啲傾去落實呢樣嘢啊，定係誒投資局管理局一齊參與啊，政府一齊參與啊，咁點樣去高度劃一法嗰個高度劃？
啊！
The trustee has to send these letters to the affected accounts.
受託人唔係嗰個成員，咁六六個月之後咧就會有四廿二人，四廿二日之後再十四日，噉係。
去最終決定，即係真真係違規嘅話，就係管理局自己去決定翻，你罰幾多或者係係咪掟佢牌之類嗰啲噉嘅嘢。
which is up at the moment. The way this works is so, what kicks off on the first of April is the six-month transitional period. So within that first six months.
噉啊，第三個最最後問題就係嗰個違規嘅後果，嗰個所後邊有講過罰款，嗰罰款咧係咪喺條例度已經寫明寫明曬？噉就但係就係由管理局。
如果噉係咪六十六十天，即係話誒一三六十八一百八十日之後，再四日、二日、再十四日之後，咁咪變咗係二零一七年年底先真真正要落實，係咪咁計啊？定係話喺嗰六十天之內都包埋呢四日二十四日咁？
We're leaving it up to them as to when. In that, some want to do it all at once, some want to spread it out across their membership. Most are inclined to do it earlier rather than later in the six months, but they've got six months to send that letter out. Once the letter is sent out,
exceptional cases in that, but for the vast majority of affected accounts, which is only a subset of the overall accounts, of course, this will be completed within that six plus six months plus 42 days plus 14 days. I haven't actually got the calendar on me, but that is the end of October, mid-November, so by early December.
Chairman, let me try to answer those. In terms of the development of the details, that's been a very broad church contributing to that. I outlined at the commencement the process we've been through in developing this. So the public consultation even included many of these investment parameters. So that goes right back to two thousand and fourteen. Even
Before then, we've been talking to the industry in some detail about how to do this, but we had regard to other things too. The industry didn't get exactly everything they wanted in terms of the investment strategy, because as I said, we used some external consultants from the OECD to give us do some scenario analysis for us on what was the best investment approach. Ultimately, of course, we came.
We came to Legco with these proposals in the bill, and some of those were discussed at length here. So there's been a lot of input into that investment approach. I think the industry certainly agrees, as a consensus at the end of the day, that it represents the best approach as a default. It's not right for everyone individually, and individuals.
might want to look at it. Does it suit my circumstances? And they may choose something else. But when looking to how to structure for default, it's consistent with international practice, consistent with the research we've got, and is based on consensus with the industry and indeed I hope the legislature, because these were discussed here. In terms of the timetable.
The member has forty two days to respond. Only at the end of that forty second day does the next fourteen days kick in. So, within the fourteen days after the forty second day, the trustee, if they haven't got a response, has to move that account into the default investment strategy. So, if you take the absolute.
Okay.
二零一七。
噉啊！
大家有冇其他問題？
我諗大致上，我哋。
去到十一月三十號嘅嚇，咁大家有冇意見？
嗱，如果冇咧，噉我哋就去睇睇個立法程序個時間表。
誒，響十一月廿五號咧，就首先向內會就提交呢個報告。
咁而家我哋嗰個審議期屆滿日期咧，就係定咗喺十一月十六號。
咁誒，正話咧講咗，就話生效日期公告就會喺二零一七年四月一日起咧就實施嘅。
噉我哋就大家同意，就將呢個期限咧，就由十一月十六號咧，就延展至十二月七號。
噉就誒動議修訂呢個附屬法例作出嘅預告期咧，亦都係需要五天嘅，咁變咗嗰度咧就會去。
albeit subject to the normal review cases. Some of this is subject to review committee, and all of it will be subject to judicial review as necessary.
因為之後咧，我哋就要啊向內務委員會啊提交報告嘅。咁如果係按照十二月七號嗰個日期咧，我哋就將會。
噉啊，我諗呢個有啲急，因為今日已經十一號啦。咁所以咧，就如果大家冇特別意見嘅咧，我就建議就誒改到去十二月七號。
outliers on that simple design. There are a few exceptions to this. I'll just come to in a second. But so the latest this could possibly happen in the simple case would be the letter would go out the last day of the tenth month, so the end of October. Add forty two days to that for the response period, and within twelve days.
After that, the money would be moved over. So within that time frame, in the normal case, would be the last date that all this transition would be finished. The exceptional cases are there are some special rules in the legislation about cases where there is returned mail because it wasn't received. The trustee has to in effect do the process again. So there are some.
The penalties, yes. The law, like any of the other financial penalty decisions within the law, is left to discretion of the authority. And any decision about revoking or suspending trustees or their administration of a scheme is, as in other cases, left to discretion of the authority.
多謝各位。
O.K.如果冇嘅咧，噉我諗啊。
大家有冇？大家認為有冇需要再開再開會？
呢個委員會有關要處理嘅東西咧，都完成咗㗎啦。咁誒？
我哋就係啦，除非有特別事情咧，我哋就啊依個會議咧就完結嘅啦。噉我哋就啊今日嘅會議咧就結束。